Gianluca Mihai Guran

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Address: 323 Hagley Rd, B17 8ND, Birmingham, UK **Mobiles:**, +447521222631 (UK), +393393753706 (ITA)

E-mail: gianluca.guran@gmail.com

Linkedin Profile: https://it.linkedin.com/in/gianluca-mihai-guran-79254950

Personal Website: https://gianlucaguran.github.io/Portfolio/

Nationality: Italian - European

PROFILE

I'm a professional programmer with more than 4 years of experience and a 2 year MSc in Computer Science. I'm currently attending Gamer Camp Pro, a postgraduate course at Birmingham City University covering the specialist skills necessary to work in the video games industry, with a strong focus on C++ and best practices related to videogame development.

Over the years I had various software development experiences, which allowed me to become proficient with different technologies and languages.

I like to consider myself a versatile person, as I am able to learn quickly and to adapt to different contexts.

I have a good problem-solving attitude, and I'm a focused and creative type: I use these qualities to deliver the most elegant and clean possible solutions to every issue.

EDUCATION

September 2016 – September 2017	Birmingham City University – Gamer Camp Pro
	1 Year MSc in Videogame Development
October 2007 – March 2011	University of Catania
	2 year MSc in Computer Science (Distinction)
October 2003 – July 2007	University of Catania
	BSc in Computer Science (2.1)
Sept 1998 – July 2003	Istituto Tecnico "E. De Nicola", San Giovanni La Punta, Italy
	High School Diploma

WORK EXPERIENCES

Independent Developer / Freelance - Catania, Italy

Working on personal and portfolio projects.

January 2015 - September 2016

Catania Science Museum, "Città delle Scienze" - Catania, Italy

Science Museum of Catania, led by the University of Catania.

March 2014 - November 2014

"Sun Tower Defense" game

Serious game about energy and photovoltaics theme ("tower defense" genre)

Unity Developer

- C# Coding
- Level building
- Asset control and optimization
- Most of game design
- Elaboration of most of the "serious" content (explanation texts, formulae and values consistency, etc.)
- Documentation of coding and design.
- Testing
- Deploy on target machines (Museum PCs)

Software Engineering Italia s.r.l. - Catania, Italy

March 2014 - October 2014

Software House in Catania, specialized in neuropsychiatry support software products.

VESPA" Project

 $Application \ which \ virtualizes \ neuropsychiatry \ tasks \ and \ tests \ for \ subjects \ of \ various \ types \ of \ mental \ retardation$

Unity Developer

- C# Coding
- Design of application components
- 3D Assets modelling and texturing
- Team mentoring (teached other team members how to develop using Unity)
- Estabilishment of development and asset organization conventions
- Testing
- Targets: PC, Android

Drakkar Dev S.r.l. - Catania, Italy

October 2011 - February 2012

Indie mobile gaming software house in Catania

Guardians: Last Day of the Citadel (Android version - unpublished)

Android porting of iOS fantasy runner game

Unity Developer - Internship

- C# Coding
- Level building, addition of version specific features in the game levels
- Testing, bug detection and correction
- Maya tool development (MEL scripting)
- Android plugin development (Java + Android SDK)
- Android App development (Java + Android SDK)

Dokroton Entertainment s.n.c - Catania, Italy

September 2008 - November 2009

Indie gaming software house in Catania

Ed01 game demo (unpublished)

Beat-em-up/action game.

Vicious Engine Developer - Internship

- Vicious Engine development
- Implementation of gameplay features
- Asset control and conversion

Longo & Longo s.a.s. - Cosenza, Italy

March 2008 - August 2008

Small ICT Company in Cosenza, specialized in web and multimedia software

Imagination Tools

A application for sound synthesis with a 3D inteface.

C++ Developer

 $\bullet \qquad \text{Design and implementation of user interface features and functions}.$

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCES

Atlas Reply S.r.l. - Milan, Italy

November 2012 - November 2013

IT Consultant: Java EE, Oracle PL-SQL, and Powercenter development

NTT Data - Milan, Italy July 2012 - October 2012

IT Consultant: Java EE and Oracle PL-SQL development

Accenture Technology Solutions - Milan, Italy

July 2012

IT Consultant: Java development

Net Service s.r.l. - Catania, Italy December 2006 - February 2007

Intern: Research on c# implementation of digital signature